&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：我想我最大的负面影响是他们选择了
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: I guess my biggest negative is that they chose to
使用他们必须在JavaScript之上分层的语法。
use a syntax that they had to layer on top of JavaScript.
也许有一天，JavaScript会在其中标准化这种语法。
And some day, maybe JavaScript standardizes this syntax in it.
他们必须做的就是为它定义一个外部标准。
What they've had to do is essentially go and define an external standard for it.
并不是没有规范，而是一种外部标准，
It's not that there is no spec, but it's an external standard,
不是JavaScript标准。
not a JavaScript standard.
当然，在这一点上我们看不到任何保证，甚至是可能性
And there's certainly no guarantee or even likelihood at this point that we see in
TypeScript或Flow正是可能最终出现在一些假想JavaScript中的东西。
TypeScript or Flow is exactly what might end up in some hypothetical JavaScript.
但这是几年后的事了，我们又不是有第三阶段的提议
But it is years away, it's not like we have a stage three proposal to
很快就会在JavaScript中添加类型。
add typing to JavaScript at any point soon.
如果真的发生了，那就太离谱了。
This is way far out if it ever happens.
我认为它创造了一种生态系统
And I think it creates a sort of ecosystem
无论何时选择特定语法和特定类型的工具，都要锁定
lock-in whenever you choose a particular syntax and a particular kind of tooling
这不是可移植的，因为它与JavaScript不同。
that isn't portable, because it isn't the same as what JavaScript is.
JavaScript之所以获胜，是因为它是如此无处不在，但现在我们将自己锁定在
JavaScript won because it's so ubiquitous, but then now we're locking ourselves into
这种生态系统虽然很受欢迎，但并不一定是无处不在的。
this ecosystems that even though it's popular, is not necessarily as ubiquitous.
所以我想这是我最大的挫折之一，或者说是我最大的犹豫。
And so I guess that's one of my biggest frustrations or my biggest hesitations.
现在，当我看到这些工具出现时，我确实非常高兴
Now, it is true that I was actually very pleased when I saw that these tools came
提供了一种只使用代码就可以进行键入注释的方法
out with a way that you can do their typing annotations using only code
评论。
comments.
所以至少在这种情况下，你没有把自己锁在
So at least in that scenario, you haven't locked yourself into
如果我不使用这个工具，这个代码就不能运行，好吗？
if I don't use this tool this code literally can't run, all right?
如果你愿意，那是一种逃逸阀，这是一件好事，但是
That's sort of an escape valve if you will, and that's a good thing, but
几乎没有人使用代码注释。
almost nobody's using the code comments.
每个人都在使用内联语法注释。
Everybody's using the inline syntax annotations.
因此会发生很多锁定现象
And so there is a lot of lock-in that happens and
我想我已经呆了足够长的时间，对这种锁定保持警惕。
I guess I've been around long enough to be wary of those sorts of lock-ins.
还有一件事，我特意在这里加了一个星号，但本质上是使用
Another thing, and I've got an asterisk here on purpose, but essentially using
这些工具需要一个构建过程，这在某种程度上提高了进入的壁垒。
those tools requires a build process which kinda raises the barrier to entry.
唯一的原因就是你不需要有构建过程
And the only reason that you wouldn't be required to have the build process
如果您使用代码注释方法和
is if you did that code comments approach and
然后就没有从系统中得到任何好处。
then got no benefit from the system whatsoever.
所以没人会这么做。
So nobody would do that.
没有人会不厌其烦地编写所有这些代码注释和
Nobody would go to all the trouble to write all those code comments and
然后根本不在编译器中使用该工具，然后直接发布它。
then not use the tool at all in the compiler and then ship it directly.
所以他们本质上需要这个构建过程。
So they're essentially requiring this build process.
和构建过程现在确实很常见，但是
And build processes are definitely common these days, but
同样，作为一个老学生，能够编写JavaScript文件和
again as an old schooler it's nice to just be able to write a JavaScript file and
直接将其加载到页面中，而不具有以下复杂性
load it directly into a page without having the complexity of
一些特定管道中的十几个工具。
a dozen tools in some particular pipeline.
所以我并不是很喜欢我们对未来想学习的开发人员说
And so I'm not a big fan of us saying to future developers that wanna learn
顺便说一句，JavaScript，你还必须学习所有这些DevOps和
JavaScript, by the way, you also have to learn all this DevOps and
只是为了编写您的第一行JavaScript。
stuff just to write your first line of JavaScript.
如果TypeScript代表了我希望JavaScript的未来，
If TypeScript represented what I hope the future of JavaScript would be,
令我烦恼的是打字稿是这样做的
what bothers me is that TypeScript is done in such a way
他们将永远被锁定在构建过程中。
that they're gonna be locked into that build process forever.
我不认为这是一个很好的进入壁垒。
And I don't think that's great as a barrier to entry.
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：从同样的讨论中流出的是
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Kind of flowing from that same discussion would be that there is
当你制作非常复杂的工具时，
a trade-off when you make really sophisticated tools,
就是你创造了一个表面区域，它很快就变得复杂了。
is that you create a surface area which gets complex very quickly.
我所展示的例子之间的区别，只是某种
The difference between the examples that I've showed, which were just some sort of
基本的分层类型，当您开始分层时，例如泛型和
basic layered-on types, and when you start layering in things like generics and
接口和其他类似的东西，你很快就会得到一种风格
interfaces and other things like that, you rapidly, rapidly get to a style of
看起来根本不像JavaScript的代码。
code that doesn't look even remotely like JavaScript.
在我看来，它看起来像Haskel。
It looks like Haskel, in my estimation.
我不是那种意思，我不是说，
And I don't mean that in a sort of, I don't mean that in a way to say,
打字是不好的，因为情况就是这样，但那是非常可怕的。
TypeScript's bad because that's the case but that is very intimidating.
我的意思是我花了很多时间和精力在这里尝试研究
I mean I'm spending time and lots of mental effort here trying in the research
在这门课上试图弄清楚这件事，而且
for this course trying to figure this stuff out, and
我开始阅读它的一些高级功能。
I start reading through some of the advanced features of this.
我只是完全迷失了所有这些角括号嵌套在一起
And I just got completely lost with all these angles brackets nested all over
那个地方什么的。
the place and stuff.
语法的复杂性呈指数级爆炸。
The syntax explodes exponentially in complexity.
我认为如果有人使用这些复杂的功能，
And I think if anyone were using those sophisticated features,
我无法想象他们雇佣一个开发人员不是已经非常，非常
I cannot imagine them hiring a developer on that was not already very, very
强大的类型脚本开发人员，他们有任何线索如何处理代码库。
strong TypeScript developer, them having any clue what to do with the code base.
所以再一次，进入壁垒上升得非常快，
So again, that barrier to entry ramps up very,
随着您开始使用越来越多的工具，速度非常快。
very quickly as your start to use more and more of that tool.
我想可能是我最后的挫败感或者
And I guess maybe the final frustration that I have or
我与这些工具共享的不同之处在于，我不
the difference that I share with these tools is that I don't
我认为考虑静态类型的想法是JavaScript的DNA。
think it's in the DNA of JavaScript to consider the idea of static typing.
也就是说容器，诸如变量和参数以及返回和
That is that containers, things like variables and parameters and returns and
属性，它们必须永远只有一种类型。
properties, that they necessarily must only have one type always and forever.
可能有一些地方这样做是有益的，比如返回类型转换
There can be some places where that's beneficial like the return type-over
函数，但是变量，我想，
function but variables, I guess,
具体地说，我不认为这是在DNA中键入我们的变量。
specifically, I don't think that's within the DNA to type our variables.
如果你想到JavaScript到底是什么，实际上是任何动态语言
If you think of what JavaScript really is and in fact any dynamic language
它是一种值类型语言，而不是变量类型语言。
it's a language that is value typing, not variable typing.
所以这感觉像是强加在JavaScript之上的错误的东西。
And so this feels like the wrong thing foisted on top of JavaScript.
从根本上来说，我觉得这不是，这是一种背叛，
It feels fundamentally to me like it's not, it's a betrayal,
它不尊重JavaScript的工作方式。
it's not respecting the way JavaScript works.
它试图把它变成不同的东西。
It's trying to make it into something different.
有些人试图把它变成不同的东西，因为他们认为
And some people are trying to make it into something different because they think
JavaScript目前是不够的。
what JavaScript currently is, is insufficient.
它坏了，还不够好。
That it's broken, that it's not good enough.
我认为JavaScript非常棒。
I think JavaScript is fantastic.
所以我不认为我们需要修复JavaScript。
So I don't think we need to fix JavaScript.
我认为这可能是最强烈的呼唤之一。
That I think is probably one of the strongest callings.
所以这里有一个很大的分歧，在这个工具可以做的伟大的事情之间
So there's a big divide there, between the great things that this tooling can do for
生态系统，以及使用它的团队，以及
the ecosystem, and for the teams that are using it, and
我认为有一些非常严重的不利因素，在两者之间应该有更多的选择。
I think some really strong downsides, and there should be more options in between.
这就是为什么我开始讨论的时候说我想扩大讨论范围
And it's why I started this discussion by saying I wanna broaden the discussion
来自这两个商标，比如TypeScript和
from just specifically these two trademarks like TypeScript and
流到关于类型感知衬里的想法的更大的讨论。
Flow to a larger discussion about the idea of type aware linting.
类型感知衬里作为一个想法是有用的和重要的。
The type aware linting as an idea is useful and important.
TypeScript和Flow是两种特殊的方式，但是
And TypeScript and Flow are two particular ways of doing it, but
不是唯一的方法。
not the only ways of doing it.